hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and I've been doing this
podcast for a couple years now the
intention is to help coaches mentors
trainers thought leaders and authors
make more money in their businesses I've
personally built seven different seven
figure mentorship and coaching
businesses three of those businesses hit
eight figures and now I'm passing on my
lessons to you of everything of what's
working what work
and what you need to do to get results
in your business
listen I'm not the best most polished
speaker I'm not perfect at anything that
I do but I got information that's going
to help you and that's what this podcast
is so you're going to get the most
authentic version of me on here today I
want to talk about being self assured
and being sure of yourself and and it's
funny cuz this is a lesson that I've had
to learn recently that I think if I had
learned it sooner man it would have I
would have made way more money
um I'm still processing through some of
these lessons but I'm going to share
some stuff that I know is going to help
you a lot which is awesome
so last
week I did a live webinar and a guy came
on
and you know whether he meant it or not
he was scrutinizing my results he was
scrutinizing the our numbers that I
claimed quote unquote and and I felt put
on the spot and I realized you know what
first off
if I look back at my track record if I
look back at what I've done of what I've
accomplished I got no reason to second
guess myself or question can I help
people and does does my system work and
and it's not just that it works for me
but we have literally thousands of our
clients have made six figures we have
hundreds that have made Seven figures
over the years that we've coached that
we've worked
with and
that's that's a result of the systems
that we teach people every single week
and and yet there are still people who
come into my space and they say Jeremiah
what you teach doesn't work by the way
they haven't actually tried it they've
never applied it they never gone through
a training they never tried to do what I
teach but they're just
assuming or they say Jeremiah you're not
I some the other day you're not
qualified to teach somebody took a look
at my backdrop they said you're in a
teenager's Li
bedroom acting like a child you got no
business credibility and I'm
like you know if I let others
opinions affect me I wouldn't be able to
build a business our business in the
last year has done over a million
dollars in my business and I wouldn't
have reached that level worrying what
anybody thinks about me concerned
with am I being approved of are other
people approving of me are they liking
me are they are they agreeing with my
truth and it's not subjective truth it's
the actual truth but to
them the truth is not true because they
somehow can't see it people literally
can't see that somebody who has a
backdrop with video games behind them
could ever have business credibility and
that's okay and it's not my job to
convince that person that I should it's
not my job to convince or prove somebody
who's trying to scrutinize my number if
I'm Legit or not and see this is the
thinking that you got to get as a mentor
and
Coach see we think if only I can prove
to
people then they'll do business with me
no no no no no it's the opposite give up
let go of stop trying to prove yourself
of anybody and be self assured believe
in yourself regardless of who agrees
with you who thinks it's true who tries
to knock you down who's negative about
it who tells you that you can't you know
I had I I had for the longest time
people they would they would come in and
they would tell me that the fact that I
wouldn't um go into business with them
for a percentage of their sales proved
that I didn't know what I was
doing no it just proves that I have
respect and boundaries for myself and my
business and so there will always be
people no matter how much good you do no
matter how many people you help that are
going to be negative that are going to
not agree with what you're talking about
that are going to try to get you to
second guess
yourself because they they don't see how
it's possible and you don't fit into the
tiny little box of life that they have
convinced themselves that reality
operates
in that's really what it
is is is that they have a version of
reality and you are so outside of that
reality that they're like yeah can't be
real can't be
true and so I want you to think think
about that when impostor syndrome comes
in impostor
syndrome affects
everybody and man it has nothing to do
with your results track record or
credibility
whatsoever has everything to do much do
with how much you believe in
yourself and you might say well Jeremiah
I want to be humble I don't want to be
arrogant I don't want to assume I know
everything about
everything I hear this from people
time like we're so
concerned with looking right to
people fitting into the box of what
people say we should
do that we
legitimately
detach our business our thinking our
creativity from what actually produces
results see why am I harping on this so
much right now why does this matter that
I took a whole podcast to talk
about it has everything to do with your
success it has everything to do with
your ability to actually make the
finances that you want is to in the face
of scrutiny negativity and even
people listen people are good talkers
they're good
gaslighters I had a lady a couple months
ago I mean she she almost got me to not
believe in myself
because of how well
she understood how to break people down
to fit into her box there are people who
literally get off on breaking you down
in order to get you to not believe in
yourself you might say oh that sounds
terrible as a mentor and as a coach you
are going to come face to face with
those people no matter how much good
you're doing no matter how much results
you have and they they literally Al get
a high off of getting you to no longer
feel confident in
yourself there's a whole group of people
out there it's just like I don't even
understand them but they exist and if
you're not careful and if you're dealing
with certain traumas if you're dealing
with certain
unhealed parts of you that are seeking
validation as I was that are seeking
approval from others as I was it might
trip you up it might knock you up it
might get you to second guess yourself
temporarily and I can tell you listen
anytime that I've ever second guess
myself I
unwisely took way too long to consider
is what this person is saying about me
true is what there is there any truth
behind their
crism listen I'm all for feedback that
helps us grow
from chosen voices in our lives that we
have asked for their
opinion but we got to stop listening to
all the negative
naysayers and trying to get other people
to validate our worth and just come to
the table with self
assurance believing in yourself
regardless of if anybody agrees with
you regardless of if anybody even thinks
think it's
true I can say this is one of the number
one areas of success in my life and by
the way every single time that I
believed in myself in these areas it was
true but I had people telling me
Jeremiah there's no flipping
way there's no way I have had people my
my my whole life telling me there's no
way you should just give up you should
just stay in your lane you know these
ways that people they think sometimes
they think they're
helping I sometimes they think they're
helping other people from not getting
scammed I've actually I had somebody
tell me that they're like Jeremiah I
want you to not believe in yourself so
you don't scam others I'm like what the
heck they they literally get off on
taking on
responsibility for other people's
emotions opinions
and it's just it's crazy like the levels
that people go to in this industry to
try to invalidate other people and so
this why I say this like you got to let
go of other people's opinions you got to
let go of trying to get people to agree
with you you got to let go of trying to
make people like
you make people see your
worth and just help the people that love
you just focus on the ones that love
connecting with you focus on the ones
that that see your worth focus on the
ones that truly resonate with your
message instead of trying to to
convince people that they should
resonate with your message connect with
the ones that do
already you might say well nobody's
connected with my message they're all
negative listen that was the case when I
started it was but it started the root
was my own internal self-talk
self-belief and not believing in myself
I even had some Twisted religious
teaching that was telling me that to be
self- assured meant that I wasn't
trusting
God what a load of
Croc like craziness absolutely
craziness and I can tell you this to
this day I I've I've met every single
financially successful person that I
know they have a level of self assurance
that goes beyond what society says is
normal they believe in
themselves I did a study for a while on
Behavior
of
narcissists and one of the behaviors
that sometimes people say is and this is
the key an overinflated sense of self
but see here's the thing a narcissist is
looking for validation from others to
prove their overinflated sense of self
here's the difference that I'm talking
about you don't need anybody to approve
of you you don't need to make anybody
approve of you you don't need to prove
yourself to
anybody and I and truly actually believe
that that's a foundation that humility
comes from it is I believe in myself so
much that I don't need you to agree with
me I'm willing to learn from any source
of course I mean my goodness I would I I
would not be the man I am today if I
wasn't willing to learn from a wide
range of people but negativity trying to
grind you down in your
self-belief that is that is a game that
I do not engage
with and and the crazy part is the
people that try to get you to play that
game they're going to try to convince
you that to not engage with them means
that you
are fraudulent bad wrong in some way
whatever cuz they have a
belief truly what I found is these
people that are like that they have an
overinflated sense of their their own
opinion let's get real here the people
that are going to try to grind you down
like that they believe that their
opinion is greater than your truth and
that you must come into alignment and
validate their opinion that is actually
by
definition narcissistic abusive
Behavior
interesting that as mentors and
coaches that we actually come up against
this with
people where people actually start to
project and I and I and these people I'm
I'm
like goodness like I meet them all the
time I'm like I I can't help them I'm
I'm not able
to but I'm not even going to try to
figure them out at that point they never
become a client I've never had any of
those types of people pay me money or
become a
client but I but I run into them often
online and and so what I've learned is
is like don't play their
game believe in yourself so much that no
matter who tries to tell you that you
don't measure up it doesn't
matter it doesn't even phase
you you don't even have to be
condescending about it that's the next
level of growth you don't need to defend
yourself that's the next level of growth
you don't need to prove yourself that's
the next level of
growth and that's where that's where I'm
at today you know now when somebody's
like that
I asked them with curiosity hey you know
is there anything in the in the training
that you did like that I shared if
they're being so negative right you know
um but coming from a place of I fully
believe in myself regardless of what
anybody says regardless of what anybody
thinks that's where financial success
flows
from that's where the ability to create
content without having to map it out and
plan it out for weeks at a time comes
from as I know like for this for this
podcast I had like few talking points I
want to talk about but I'm just flowing
intuitively while I'm talking right now
in front of the camera I'm just I'm it's
like I'm having a conversation with my
group I'm just sharing I didn't spend
hours mapping out what I'm talking about
right now I just pressed record on a
Sunday
afternoon and here we
are why
because I believe in my message so much
that I don't need it to be perfect I
don't need to say everything perfect I
don't need to sound perfect I had
somebody say so does I I had somebody
tried to tell me that by being that way
it means that I have no respect for my
clients I have no respect for other
people because I'm not willing to put my
best foot forward my goodness what kind
of ridiculous messaging to try to
invalidate people people hurl what kind
of crazy
gatekeeping BS is tossed around in the
coaching industry it's Insanity to
me get rich make money I had saw
somebody the other day say if you're
using chat GPT in your coaching business
you're a fraud well goodness been using
it for two years our clients are making
a ton of
money like I don't
care
period
and I want to see
people getting
results producing results your success
in business starts with believing in
yourself regardless of who in your life
is trying to tell you that you shouldn't
that you're not good enough yet that
you're not qualified that you haven't
reached a certain
level of case studies or results to be
able to do the thing that you want to do
I say fooy with
that believe in
yourself your level of
self-belief and your income are directly
correlated to each other I stand by that
more than anything else I heard that a
year and a half ago and it's funny I had
people try to tell me it's not true it's
so true it's absolutely
true when you believe in yourself and
you stop seeking validation from others
you stop seeking approval from other
people you stop trying to get people to
believe in you and you believe in
you
regardless of others opinions of you
listen I'm shaking the Paradigm of what
you might have been taught your whole
life there are some of you you might be
listening to this right now and you
might say Jeremiah yeah but XYZ
situation I'm not talking about other
people I'm talking about you right now
because I want to see you succeed
financially stop fighting for your
excuses stop fighting for your reasons
why you can't do
this and start realizing that this is
what separates those who are financially
successful from those who are
not I want to see you
succeed and this way of thinking will
change everything for you but you're
going to have to challenge why you don't
think this way it's going to start by
challenging what beliefs are underneath
the
surface podcasts like this can only get
you so far it goes way
deeper than just the surface level like
oh yeah that's a great podcast but
like it goes into the core of how you
operate in all areas of your life and
when you start looking at and you start
observing all all the areas where you
don't believe in yourself and you're
waiting for other people to tell you
that you're good enough and to give you
permission and to approve of you and you
start seeing that pleasing others and
quote unquote doing the right thing what
you should according to what everybody
else tells you that you should do to get
a stamp of approval from other people as
your driving motivator for Action in
your life you will start to see how this
way of thinking has a grip on your mind
and has a grip rip on everything that
you do and then you can start to unwire
it and you can start to rewire it and
you can start to make the changes that
are necessary to start to grow in your
life and create the kind of business
that you want listen I believe in you
and I believe that it is possible for
you to do this you may be listening to
this right now and you may be thinking
it is impossible for me it is
not take a look at where did this
thinking first come in if I may
everybody like me and approve of me and
I do all the right things then I will be
safe then things will go how they should
that's the
rote that's the roote realize success
comes by taking risk without knowing how
something's going to turn
out and learning to regulate yourself to
where you're not panicked or in a state
of total chaos and confusion while doing
so and that you start to embrace the
process without knowing the outcome
without predicting the
outcome that's where success comes
from and that starts with believing in
yourself that starts with saying you
know what regardless of who tries to get
me to second guess myself I will
not and I will
continue to create the life that I want
no matter who tries to stop me you know
I've had people go as far as in my life
as tell me Jeremiah your message is
dangerous and I'm going to try to stop
you from reaching other people with it
I've had people tell me that they will
make it their life mission to prevent me
from reaching other people with my
message and they've actually gone as far
as to actually go to influential people
and tell them to not interview me to not
put me on their podcast to not talk to
me that I'm dangerous that I'm not a
good person to work with people I've
never even worked with but that have
made assumptions about what I've said
about what I mean my
intentions and I still continue to do to
this day without fear without worry
without trying to manage maintain or
control what other people think about me
and that's what I want to encourage you
to do as well grow your life everybody
and we'll talk soon have a good
[Music]
one